There was a ton of really cool AI
updates this week. We have AI image
editors that could potentially replace
Photoshop. Tons of updates out of Google
and their made by Google event. And even
teases around GPT6. Yes, only a couple
weeks after GPT5, we're already talking
about GPT6. All that and more in today's
AI news breakdown. I don't want to waste
your time, so let's dive right in.
Starting with the new image editor out
of Quinn called Quinn Image Edit. Oh, I
mentioned a new image editor that could
replace Photoshop. Well, this week
there's actually two.
No. God, please no.
You've got this Quinn image edit which
comes out of Chinese company Alibaba and
is actually opened via the Apache 2.0
license. And similar to what you can do
inside of Chat GPT where you can give it
images and then tell it to, you know,
change the angle of the person or put a
hat on them or things like that. Well,
Quinn imageedit is an open version of
that. And if we look at their page here,
we could see some examples of like this
input image and then the various sort of
uh derivatives they built off of this
input image. Feel free to pause here and
see the prompts that they used. But you
can see they gave it one input image and
then gave it a prompt like the bear is
wearing an elaborate dance dress with
arms spread open performing an elegant
dancing pose. And you got this image
using this same bear here. More
examples. Input image. Obtain the front
view and it turned the person around.
And we have some more examples of the
same type of prompt. Here we can see an
input image where they change the style
to like a Giblly style and a 3D cartoon
style. Here's an input image where they
added a sign that says, "Welcome to
Penguin Beach." So, pretty much the
sky's is the limit on what type of edits
you can make to these images here. And
you can use this model totally free
right now by going to the Quinn Chat
website, which is just quin.ai. And then
once you're logged in, you'll notice
that there's a little button down in the
bottom that says image edit. We select
this image. It says upload a picture and
describe how you'd like it edited. So
this is one of their demo images here.
And it automatically plugged in this
prompt while I was testing that says
replace the polka dot shirt with a light
blue shirt. And we can see it did just
that. I'm going to go ahead and feed it
an image of myself here. And then say
give me the side view of this image. And
it actually did a really good job. I
mean that actually kind of looks like my
profile. Here's an image I uploaded of
me and my friends Molly and Joe, and I
said, "Make it nighttime with a city
skyline behind us." And a few seconds
later, I got the exact image I was
looking for. I mean, see how this could
potentially replace Photoshop. And this
is just one of two image editors that
everybody's talking about this week.
Maybe you've been hearing the term nano
banana flying around this week as well.
Well, that's because that does the same
thing, but almost feels even more
powerful than this one. But it's not
totally accessible yet. There is a
workaround to use it which I made a
whole video about a few days ago. So
check that video out if you haven't
already. But let me give you a quick
overview of what it's capable of and
then I'll give you the quick TLDDR of
how you can actually generate with it
right now. So here's some examples from
this Xacount D studio project. And we
can see they gave it a base image here
of this woman on the left with a white
purse. They gave it this image of a new
purse with the prompt change the bag
with the second image. And it put this
purse on this woman here. Another
example. Here's the base image where
she's reading a book. They give it this
image and say replace the book cover
with the cover with the second image.
And it replaced just the book cover,
leaving the rest of the image pretty
much exactly the same. Another one where
they gave this girl these glasses and
this girl this like puffer jacket here.
Here's another example from Mariano
Partardo where he was able to give it
three different images. He gave it an
image of Satia Nadella, Sundar Pinchi,
and an image of the beach and said, "Put
the two persons together on the beach in
a natural way." And you can see it made
this image with Satia and Sundar hanging
out together on this beach. And
everything stayed consistent. It's the
same beach. Maybe they're wearing
different outfits, but you can
definitely tell who it's supposed to be.
And it did a really good job. I thought
Mad Pencil here also had a really cool
example where she took this image, which
is like a realworld image. I don't know
if it was actually AI generated or this
was a real image. I'm actually guessing
it was AI generated, but she gave it the
prompt, make the ramen bowl and ramen
look like 2D whimsical handdrawn anime
illustration, keeping everything else in
the image exactly the same. And this was
the result. And I just thought this was
a really fun use case to sort of blend
real image with cartoony image. And
again, I do believe this background
image is probably AI. I can't confirm
100%, but this would work just as well
on a real image. When she gave ChatGpt
the same image and same prompt, it just
turned the whole thing into a cartoon.
Same with when she used the Quinn image
edit, the one that we were just looking
at a minute ago, Nano Banana was able to
figure out how to cartoonize just the
ramen. All the rest of the models wanted
to turn the whole image into a cartoon.
Really, really impressive. It's also
really good at colorizing black and
white photos. I actually found this
photo online and I fed it into Nano
Banana. Gave it the prompt to colorize
and upscale the photo. And here was the
output. Again, here was the original.
And here's what it made from my prompt.
I then wanted to test combining two
images. So, I gave it this image that I
found online of Steve Jobs and this
image of myself. And I gave it the
prompt, make these two men sitting next
to each other. Adjust lighting and
colors so it looks like they're in the
same room chatting. And here was the
output. I mean, it kind of gave me a
different haircut, but other than that,
everything looks really, really good. I
then fed that same image back in and
said, "Make it so the two men are
sitting on top of a skyscraper with the
city below." And this was the output
image that I got of me and Steve Jobs
sitting on a skyscraper. I then took
this same image, plugged it back in, and
gave it the prompt, make it nighttime.
And now I've got a picture of me and
Steve Jobs sitting on a skyscraper at
night. I don't know why I'm still
wearing sunglasses in it at nighttime.
I'm sure there was some bright light
shining on us or something, but really,
really, really impressive model. Now, as
of right now, it hasn't been publicly
announced who made this model. They've
been kind of keeping it a mystery. Not
really, but kind of sort of. It's a
mystery. Most people believe it's
Google. And the reason most people
believe it's Google is because Logan
Kilpatrick, who is the lead of product
over at Google AI Studio, tweeted a
picture of just a banana. and Josh
Woodward also at Google. He's the VP of
Google, Google Labs, and Gemini app.
Well, he posted this is banana, which I
think is a pretty good indicator that
Nano Banana came from Google. But again,
I mentioned it's not the easiest to use
right now. The way people have
discovered Nano Banana and started using
it was through this site LM Arena, which
is a site where you can kind of do a
blind test of models and then pick your
favorite and then it sort of ranks the
models based on which ones were blindly
picked as the favorites. And if you come
to LaMarina, you can use Nano Banana for
free, but it takes some work. So head on
over to lmarina.ai. Up at the top, you
have three options: battle, sidebyside,
and direct chat. You're only going to
get Nano Banana in the battle mode. And
well, you may not even get it on your
first try. It's the mode where it gives
you two models side by side, but they're
blind. It's not available in sideby-side
chat or direct chat, only battle mode.
Once you're in battle mode, you can turn
on generate images, and then you can
drag and drop any image in. So, I'm
going to drop this old image in of me
being interviewed by Joe Polish and give
it the prompt, upscale the quality of
this image, and make it nighttime. Also,
give me a baseball cap and submit it.
We'll see. It's going to give me two
options. It's generating it blindly with
two different models and we have no idea
which models it's going to use. It gave
me two images back. This one, which
doesn't look great, and this one, which
is okay. Doesn't really look much higher
quality, but it's okay. This one is
definitely better. We don't know which
model is which. We'll click right is
better. And we can see this was seated
3.0 and this was Gemini 2.0. We did not
get nano banana. So, I have to just do
it again until it gives me nano banana.
And on my second attempt, we can see
that it actually gave me nano banana as
one of the options. And this was the
image that it outputed. And it did
actually make it slightly higher
quality. It made it nighttime in the
background. It left everything the same.
And it put a hat on Joe Polish, which
makes sense cuz I said, "Give me a hat."
The model didn't know which one was me.
So, it's very obvious that if I would
have said, "Put a hat on the guy on the
right," it would have done a better job
of putting it on me. But, it did do a
pretty good job here. And that's how you
can currently use Nano Banana. You can
use it directly inside of LM Marina. You
just might need to prompt it a couple
times until you get the actual model,
but there's no limit to how many times
you can do it. So, you can keep on
generating it and generating it and
generating it until you get the exact
output that you want. And well, once you
get really good at this and these models
get better and better, why are you going
to need to go into Photoshop and sort of
crop around things and composite
elements into the background, it's going
to get to a point where you just either
give it an image or multiple images,
tell it what you want it to look like,
and it's going to essentially do the
photoshopping for you. Pretty sweet. You
know how the startup world works. Move
fast, validate your idea, raise capital.
But here's the thing. The first AI
companies building on Lovable are
already getting into Y Combinator and
raising a half a million dollar VC
checks before most people even have a
working prototype. And that's not luck.
It's because the future of work is
shifting. Now it's up to AI to find the
right problem to solve. AI to build and
validate your MVP and AI to keep
supporting your product as it grows. And
that's exactly what Lovable does.
Whether you're a product manager with a
game-changing idea, a designer stuck at
the handoff to dev stage, or a
non-technical founder who just wants to
get to market before the window closes.
Lovable takes your vision and turns it
into a fully functional product in
minutes. Landing pages, dashboards, SAS
apps, even complex integrations done.
You skip the dev bottleneck, wow your
team or investors, and focus on what
matters. Shipping, testing, and scaling.
No coding, no hiring headaches, no long
delays. Just describe it and Lovable
builds it, keeping your vision intact
while freeing you up to move 10 times
faster. So, if you've been sitting on an
idea that can change your career or your
life, don't wait for someone else to
beat you to it. Check out the link in
the description, start building with
Lovable, and join the wave of founders
who are proving that in the AI era, the
only limit is how fast you're willing to
launch. Thanks so much to Lovable for
sponsoring today's video. Now, let's get
back to it. If you want to use a
platform where you can do this kind of
editing, Higsfield AI also rolled out
this feature. Now, this video makes it
look like they're doing this with
videos, but what they're really doing is
they're changing the starting image and
that starting frame is becoming the
beginning of a video. So, it's the same
thing. They're editing images by giving
them products and things like that and
then converting it into videos using
things like V3. So, a feature that's
available in Higsfield if you want to
try it there as well. I don't know
exactly which model they're using. If I
had to guess, it's probably the
QuinnEdit model, but I'm not 100% sure
on that. Runway ML rolled out some new
features this week, including this
Runway Game Worlds beta. So, it says
game worlds employs novel uses of AI for
nonlinear narrative experiences, meaning
every game session you play is generated
in real time with personalized stories,
characters, and multimodal media
generation. So, it appears to create
this like textbased game for you. But as
it's doing this textbased game, it's
generating images to go along with the
game. So it's not just reading text.
It's like reading a book but with
pictures. And they're making it
available right now over at
play.runwayml.com.
And I'm not 100% sure if it's fully
available or if it's just creative
partner program that it's available for.
I believe it's for everybody cuz it
doesn't have any sort of specifics
around who can use it. And when I
clicked on this link, it let me into
mess around with it. So I can create a
game world. What's the name of your game
world? I called mine Apocalyptic
Wasteland. And then I just clicked
autocomplete and it built out the
description for me just based on the
name of the game. And then under
advanced options here, you can see it
plugged in the genre, art style, game
mechanics, how do you win, how do you
lose, all of that kind of stuff. And now
we can just click next. And it's
generating an image for our game. And
here's what it generated. So, let's
click create game world, and we're in.
You must journey through a world
reclaimed by colossal otherworldly flora
and the lingering emotional echoes of a
cataclysm, seeking scattered ancient
relics to mend humanity's spiritual
wounds. All right. What is the name of
your character? Let's go, Mattius. Nice
to meet you, Mattius. We can now
generate your avatar. Upload an image
for reference, or feel free to skip this
step if you prefer not to. Yeah, sure.
Let's upload a reference image. Give it
my image here, and let's go ahead
generate with image. Here's my game
avatar that looks like me but in this
world. Let's click continue. And now
it's creating your world. My main quest
is unite the heart shards. Seek and
activate the ancient relics to mend
humanity's spiritual wounds. And so we
can see as we play through the game, it
almost looks like a comic book. Your
throat burns. Each breath a dry rasp
against the still humid air. I start
with plus 100 vitality, plus one water
supply. The giant twisted roots of a
verdant scar loom above, offering no
shade. A distant shimmer catches your
eye. A mirage of clear water in the dust
choke distance. So, you can see how this
is like basically the same concept as a
textbased like adventure or fantasy
game, except we get images to go along
with it, so we don't have to like try to
visualize it all in our head. A faint
melancholic hum resonates from a crack
in a nearby root, revealing a glimmering
crystalline fragment. The shard pulses
with a strange energy tugging at your
spirit while your body craves water.
Will you pursue the possible water or
investigate the glowing shard? And then
it gives me some options here or I can
type in my own. Let's examine the shard.
You move towards the pulsing light. The
thirst in your throat temporarily
forgotten. Now my water supply is minus
one. As your fingers brush the shard, a
wave of profound sorrow, then fleeting
joy washes over you. I mean, this is
really actually kind of fun, especially
since it's like injecting me into the
game and I'm seeing the images as I go.
The shard vibrates. A faint whisper of
laughter and song echo in your mind.
Brief glimpses of a world that once was.
It also seems like it could be a
colossal time waster, but it's kind of
fun. So, you get the idea. I'm not going
to keep on playing here on this
recording cuz I will probably just get
lost in this world and get further and
further sucked in, but this is super
cool. Not like the most useful
productive thing ever, but if you just
want to kill some time and get lost in
this fantasy game, this seems like a
great way to do it. Since we're talking
about Runway, they also rolled out some
like quality of life features this week.
Like they're adding third-party models
directly inside of their chat mode.
You'll be able to use VO3 inside of
Runway. They've updated the way the chat
looks so your chat stays on the left and
all your generations on the right so you
can, you know, see them both side by
side as you have a conversation and
improve your videos. And they're also
bringing the Gen 4 image turbo mode to
all users, which is a really, really
fast model. 11 Labs dropped another
feature update this week as well. This
week they launched a new video to music
flow in 11 Lab Studio. In one click, 11
Music model generates a custom
soundtrack based on your video's
context. After adding music, you can
layer in voiceovers and sound effects
directly inside of the studio. So, to
me, this seems like it could potentially
replace a lot of those like stock music
websites. No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
You give it a video and it figures out
based on what's going on on the video
what kind of background music will go
with that video. Here's some examples
like the music they put over this like
raining on a leaf here.
[Music]
I believe they also added the like rain
sound effects using 11 Labs. Here's
another one.
a sort of synth wave cyberpunk song for
that video. Grand awinspiring outdoor
scene
[Music]
and it figures all that out by just
giving it a video. It's available to try
over at 11labs.io/studio/videotomusic.
But here you could just upload a video.
Here's an AI generated video of me
dancing. I wonder what it's going to do
for this one. I'll just drop it in here.
It's watching my video. And here's what
it gave us.
So, it knew it was kind of like a 70s
vibe and it gave it sort of 70s vibe
music. Pretty cool. What do you think?
Are stock music websites in trouble?
Google also updated their AI mode in
search this week. Now it's got more
agentic features. So the example they
give here is you can now ask about
getting a dinner reservation with
friends that includes multiple
constraints and preferences like party
size, date, time, location, and
preferred cuisine. Now this is a feature
that needs to be turned on. So if you
have access to Google Labs, you'd click
on this little search labs button and
then make sure you have AI mode turned
on and then you can try AI mode. But
let's try something like find me a nice
restaurant in downtown San Diego for
Saturday night that serves sushi and can
seat up to 8:00. We want to eat sometime
between 6:00 p.m. and 7:00 p.m. and it
should be somewhat close to the
ballpark. So, we can walk to the game.
So, if I give it all of that information
and send it, let's see what happens. And
we can see that it found me a bunch of
sushi restaurants with high ratings
downtown. It looked for them near Petco
Park. And then down at the bottom, to
ensure seating for a group of eight,
it's recommended to make a reservation,
especially since you plan to dine on a
Saturday night. So, I mean, it did find
all the information for me, but it
didn't like take a ton of actions on my
behalf. It just sort of pulled all that
information together for me and gave me
a good response. There's also a new like
quality of life feature inside of Google
Docs where you can actually have it read
the doc to you with a AI voice. So, if I
open up a Google Doc here and I come up
to my tools menu, there's a new option
for audio and I can say listen to this
tab. Now, I believe this is only rolled
out on the pro and ultra plans. Like, I
think you need to have one of Google's
paid plans to be able to use this. I'm
not 100% sure, but I believe I remember
reading that it's only on the paid plans
for right now. But, we can go ahead and
click listen to this tab.
The practicality index, a blueprint for
benchmarking the real world utility of
large language models. Introduction. the
practicality gap in LLM evaluation.
So, we can see that it's actually a
pretty human sounding voice. It doesn't
sound like an old robotic AI voice. It
sounds like a real human reading it. And
pretty good quality. We also have the
ability to change the voice to a
narrator, an educator, a teacher, a
persuader, an explainer, or a coach. So,
if I switch it to coach for instance,
select that.
The practicality index, a blueprint for
we get audio that is a slightly
different voice. So, a pretty handy
feature if you want your documents read
to you. There's also some new AI
features inside of Adobe Acrobat, which
can help you do cool AI stuff with your
PDFs. I do believe you have to have like
a Google Cloud membership to be able to
use this, but they have a new feature
called PDF spaces, which allows you to
have conversations with your PDFs. It'll
allow you to easily pull data and
information from PDFs and things like
that. So, if I bust open my Adobe
Acrobat here, you can see over on the
left there's a PDF spaces link. If I
click into here, this is the new PDF
spaces feature. I'll pull in this ebook
called Mastering LLM as a judge. Just
drag it right in here. Opens it up in
Adobe. I'm going to click add to PDF
space. And we can see that similar to
like notebook LM, it pulled in a bunch
of information that it grabbed from this
PDF here, including even making like a
little table of details from the PDF.
And then there's various assistants. We
can see choose an assistant. Down on the
bottom, you have an analyst, an
entertainer, and an instructor. And I
could do things like put it on
entertainer. And it seems to reconfigure
all of this content here for a more
entertaining read. LLMs can be like a
mysterious magician. Impressive, but
you're left wondering how they pulled
off the trick. So, just another way for
you to interact with your PDFs directly
with inside of Adobe and quickly pull
out details. especially good for longer
PDFs or more complicated technical PDFs.
This week was also Google's annual made
by Google event. This is like Google's
annual hardware event where they
announce all the latest things they've
done with like their Pixel phones and
things like that. And of course, since
it's Google, everything rolled out with
AI. Now, I'm not going to get super deep
into everything they announced at this
made by Google event because there was a
lot and I don't really think we need to
get into the details about what all of
these various phones and watches do. But
I will give you a quick TLDDR of the
various like AI stuff that they've added
into these gadgets. And the people that
got to demo this stuff are absolutely
raving about how good the AI has gotten
inside of these various Google Pixel
products. So, they showed off their new
Pixel 10 phone. It's got a new chip in
it, a Tensor G5 chip, and it was
co-designed with Google Deep Mind with
the Gemini Nano model sort of at the
forefront. So, these phones are
basically built from the ground up for
ondevice AI, which is something that I
think a lot of people really, really
want. They don't want to send their
prompts off to the cloud and wait for a
response. If we can get more of this on
device, that's obviously better. And
these phones have a feature called Magic
Q. And this isn't an app. It's something
that's just always running on your
phone. And it's basically letting the AI
see what's going on on your phone so it
can give you advice and feedback and
help you jump around to different things
on the phone. So, one of the examples
they gave in their demo was somebody
texted them and said, you know, where
was the location of that concert we're
going last week? Well, in their text
message app, the AI read the text
message, went and figured out where the
location of whatever concert it was was,
and then put it into the send box so
they can just press one button and send
the location without the user actually
having to go and look around in their
calendar and, you know, find locations
and stuff. Google just sort of connected
the dots for them. So they can just
one-click reply with the answer because
the information was already on the phone
and the AI was able to sort of locate it
and pull it forward for them. And this
feature is sort of crossplatform, cross
app and is just understanding the
context of what's going on in your
phone. And this is something I wish
iPhones have cuz my main daily driver
phone is an iPhone and I really want
this feature. It looks really good. They
also show off this feature in the camera
app where it can look at your photo and
actually give you advice on how to get a
better photo while you're actually in
the process of taking the photo. You can
see ask the person to look at the camera
to create a more engaging and personal
photo. So, it's giving you advice on
what to tell the person to do. Move
closer to the person and the sculpture.
Lower the camera slightly. And it just
gives you instructions until it dials in
on what it thinks will be the best photo
for you to take. And here was the
resulting photo, which looks like a
pretty decent composition. They also
showed off that the phones can have
realtime voice translation. So you could
talk to anybody in any other language
and it will automatically translate it
on the fly in real time. That's insane.
Voice translate works when translating
from English with Spanish, German,
Japanese, French, Hindi, Italian,
Portuguese, Swedish, Russian, and
Indonesian. That is just wild to me that
I can just call somebody in Russia and
have a conversation with them. They'll
hear me in my voice speaking Russian and
I'll hear them and their voice sounding
like they're speaking English. Crazy.
They also showed off that you can edit
images with just text prompts. So you
can see remove the glare right in the
photo, etc. And then it goes and fixes
the photos based on their text prompt.
And a lot of people believe that this is
using that new nano banana technology
from Google, but that hasn't been
confirmed. It just seems like that's
most likely. It can restore old photos
and colorize them just like what we were
looking at Nano Banana. And it gives
those like Photoshop style editing
features to change the image however you
want directly inside of your phone. Like
a lot of the features they showed off
could cause me to switch to the Pixel
phone as my full-time daily driver cuz
it's all really cool stuff. They also
rolled out the Pixel Buds 2A which allow
you to talk with Gemini even without
taking out your phone. These to me look
just like the little earbuds they have
in the movie Her, which is probably kind
of what they're going for. And all you
have to do is say and you're talking
with Gemini. They showed off the Pixel
Watch 4 and it now has a personal AI
health coach. It provides proactive
fitness and sleep coaching and ondemand
guidance. And of course, it also has
Gemini, your on- wrist AI assistant. So,
a lot of the stuff you can do with
Gemini, you'll be able to do directly
from these watches. and the same AI
features and health coach that went to
that watch, they're also coming to
Fitbit. So, if you don't want to get the
full watch and the full watch
experience, but you do want that fitness
and health coach, well, you'll be able
to get it inside of the new Fitbits
pretty soon. They also announced a
Gemini for Home. So, your Google Home
devices are going to have Gemini built
into them. And they made some updates to
Gemini Live where it will actually give
you on-screen cues. Like, they took a
picture here and said, "What seasoning
do I use?" and it actually circled the
spot on the picture for him. They showed
the camera some like wrenches and asked
which one to use and it highlighted the
wrench to use. They're also making it
connect to more Google apps, Google
Calendar, Keep and Tasks are both
available today and soon. Messages,
phone and clock apps. So, a lot of the
apps that are on your phone that are in
the Google ecosystem are all going to
start to tie together a little bit
better using AI. And that's pretty much
the quick TLDDR of all of the cool sort
of AI gadgetry that came out of Made by
Google. I know I've shared a lot
already, but there's a few smaller items
that I want to put on your radar and
share with you. So, let's jump into a
quick rapid fire and I will fire off the
rest for you real quick.
We got a few new large language models
that you can use this week. Deepseek has
a new version 3.1 with 685 billion
parameters. So, it's a big big model.
You can make it think or turn off the
thinking mode. It's apparently really
really fast. And you can use it over at
chat.deseek.com.
I haven't personally tested this one
yet, but I've heard very good things.
I've heard it's a very very impressive
model. It's got 128,000 token context
window and seems to score pretty well on
all of the various benchmarks. So, looks
like another solid model. Another model
came out of China this week as well from
Bite Dance, the company behind Tik Tok
called Seed OSS 36B. So, it's a 36
billion parameter model, but it has a
512,000
token context window, which is really,
really impressive for an open source
openweight model. Again, I haven't
tested this model myself, but I want to
make you aware of all of the newest
large language models that are dropping.
And finally, the other model that
dropped this week was from Nvidia called
Neotron Nano 9B version 2, which also
has the ability to toggle on and off
reasoning. The model also appears to be
fairly open. So, it says here, "The Nano
9B V2 model is released under the Nvidia
open model license agreement. It's
designed to be permissive and
enterprisefriendly. NVIDIA explicitly
states that the models are commercially
usable out of the box and that
developers are free to create and
distribute derivative models. So you can
use this basically as if it was an open-
source openweight model. We got a few
updates out of OpenAI this week.
Apparently they made GPT5 warmer and
friendlier based on feedback. So there's
small genuine touches like good question
and great start. Not flattery but just a
little bit friendlier I guess. And the
comments on this thread are, "Nobody
wants that. Just let us pick between our
models again." It's kind of funny.
OpenAI just can't win. Everybody hated
the fact that there was so many models
and they had to pick which model they
needed to use and nobody knew which
model to use. So, they rolled out GPT5
which basically picked the model for you
and everybody hated the fact that their
old models that they loved went away.
OpenAI brought back the old models and
then started to tweak GPT5 to be more
friendly like the old models and
everybody went, "No, don't do that. Just
give us GPT5 the way it is, but also let
us have our old models." So, it's like
OpenAI just can't seem to win.
Interestingly, even though GBT5 is only
a couple weeks old at this point, we're
already talking about GPT6. Sam Alman is
claiming that it's coming faster than
most people realize. And it seems like a
big focus of this one is enhanced
memory. Sam Alman didn't give a release
date for his company's next artificial
intelligence model, but he made clear
that GPT6 will be different and that it
will arrive faster than the gap between
GPT4 and GPT 5. It won't just respond to
users, but will adapt to them and allow
people to create chat bots that mirror
personal tastes. He sees memory as the
key for making chat GPT truly personal.
It needs to remember who you are, your
preferences, routines, quirks, and adapt
accordingly. So, the future models of
chat GPT, we actually talked about this
when I made my videos about GPT5. The
future is everybody's going to have like
their own version of chat GPT. when I
log into my chat GPT account and have
conversations with it, it's going to
respond to me completely differently
than how it would respond to you inside
of your chat GPT account because it's
going to remember what you like, your
preferences, the way you want it to
respond to you and things like that. And
they're just going to get more and more
and more tailored to exactly what you
want chat GBT to be for you. And it
sounds like that's the big goal with
GPT6. Take this with a grain of salt,
but Sam Alman also believes that we're
currently in a bubble in the AI world.
He said, "If you look at most of the
bubbles in history, like the tech
bubble, there was a real thing. Tech was
really important. The internet was a
really big deal. People got over
excited. Are we in a phase where
investors as a whole are over excited
about AI?" My opinion is yes. Is AI the
most important thing to happen in a very
long time? My opinion is also yes. So,
he's kind of comparing it to the
internet bubble. does think that it will
probably crash and valuations will
probably go down. At least that's my
take on this. However, even though there
was the internet bubble and then it
crashed, it's not like the internet went
away and there weren't still some big
winners to come out of it. And well,
this will likely be the same. Again,
that's my take on what Sam's saying.
Microsoft is rolling their co-pilot
directly into Excel. I have the newest
beta version of Excel and I don't have
it yet. Even though the report here says
that I should have it in my account by
now, but apparently you'll be able to
type in a command like equals copilot
and then have it actually do a bunch of
stuff for you. Copilot list airport
codes from major airports in E3. E3 is
USA. And you can see it automatically
filled in a bunch of airport codes. They
change it to Australia. Fills in a bunch
of airport codes from Australia. They
built that all using Copilot. Here's
another one where they put a bunch of
feedback in a list and then they gave it
a prompt of what is the sentiment of the
comment over on the left and then it
figured out if it was positive or
negative and they were able to drag and
drop that sort of code all the way down
and it automatically, you know, figured
out the sentiment of all of these
comments. So, seems like it'd be a
pretty handy feature once we can
actually use it. Their article here does
say it's rolling out to beta channel
users with a 365 Copilot license, which
I do have. I was trying to test it on
the Mac version, and I do have 16.101,
and it didn't work for me yet. So, I
don't know if I was doing something
wrong or if it isn't fully rolled out
yet, but it looks like it will be pretty
cool once it's available. Grammarly is
rolling out some new AI features which
will help with teachers grading and
students writing. Students today need AI
that enhances their capabilities without
undermining their learning. Grammarly's
new agents fill this gap, acting as real
partners that guide students to produce
better work while ensuring they develop
real skills that will serve them
throughout their careers by teaching
students how to work effectively with
AI. Now, we're preparing them for a
workplace where AI literacy will be
essential. So, we can see in the demo
here, it added like a sidebar and I
believe this is like helping them grade
this paper. see predict a grade and it's
reading the paper and I guess helping a
teacher grade the paper. So, some pretty
interesting features out of Grammarly.
Not something I've tested myself yet.
Meta is expanding their AI translation
feature and making it so your Instagram
and you know Facebook reels and things
will automatically be translated.
YouTube has already rolled out a similar
feature, but it's now coming to the meta
platforms. It says, "Meta translations
uses the sound and tone of your own
voice so it feels authentically you. And
the lip-s syncing feature matches your
mouse movements to the translated audio
so that it looks like you're really
speaking the language in the real. And
from what I gather from their article,
it looks like it's already rolled out.
Not something I've tested yet, but I am
actually spending more time on Facebook.
So if you're a Facebook person, you
could feel free to follow me over there
as well, cuz I have been posting there a
little bit more often lately. Just a
random interesting factoid for you. And
then finally, since we're talking about
Meta, it's expected that they're going
to show off their new smart glasses at
Meta Connect this year. And the rumor is
they're going to have a little display
in one of the eyes, so you can actually
have like a heads up display inside of
your glasses. Now, whether they're going
to be able to keep them in the same form
factor and keep them just as light, I
don't know. but they're expected to be
released somewhere around 800 bucks and
have a screen for apps and alerts on one
lens and a wrist accessory that can help
you control the glasses. Unfortunately,
I'm not making it out to Meta Connect
this year. I'm going to be at New York
City at a YouTube event instead. But I
am really, really excited to see these
in action. I saw Google's version of
them, you know, six or seven months ago
in person and they blew my mind. If
these come anywhere near Google's
versions, they're going to be a hit.
Everybody's going to want them. So,
really excited to see what they do with
this. But that's what I got for you
today. Again, it was a lot of news this
week. A lot of interesting stuff, a lot
of things out of Google, some cool image
editors. Hopefully, you enjoyed this
video. You feel more looped in on what's
going on with the AI world and what
you're capable of doing with AI as of
right now today. That's my goal with
this channel. And if you like videos
like this, make sure you like this one
and subscribe to this channel. and I
will make sure that more updates like
this one as well as tutorials and other
interesting news from the AI world shows
up in your YouTube feed. But once again,
thank you so much for hanging out with
me and nerding out with me in this
video. I really, really appreciate you
tuning in and uh trying to stay on the
bleeding edge of AI with me. It's been
really fun and I hope you're having fun
as well. So, thanks again and hopefully
I'll see you in the next one. Bye-bye.
Thank you so much for nerding out with
me today. If you like videos like this,
make sure to give it a thumbs up and
subscribe to this channel. I'll make
sure more videos like this show up in
your YouTube feed. And if you haven't
already, check out futuretools.io where
I share all the coolest AI tools and all
the latest AI news. And there's an
awesome free newsletter. Thanks again.
Really appreciate you. See you in the
next one.